parship.co.uk 2019-08-06

# Online Dating Service: Serious Matchmaking for Singles at Parship

### Privacy policy for the use of the Parship Website - Version: 08.03.2019

Thank you for using the Parship website! Here you will find information about which personal data Parship collects, how we handle these data and what options you have as a user. PE Digital GmbH (hereafter “Parship”) is responsible for the data processing. 

  * Contact
  * Collection, processing and use of personal data
  * Processing purposes
  * Legal basis for the processing of personal data
  * Transfer of data to third parties; service provider
  * Duration of storage; retention periods
  * Rights of the data subject at a glance
  * Cookies & web tracking
  * Web analytics
  * Social plugins

_Contact_

For information and suggestions on data protection, we or our data protection officer are at your disposal. 

If you would like to contact us, you can contact us as follows: 

PE Digital GmbH, Customer Service Parship United Kingdom, Speersort 10, 20095 Hamburg, Germany, +49 (40) 460026 - 168 (fax number), [privacypolicy@parship.co.uk](mailto:privacypolicy@parship.co.uk) (email) 

**Our data protection officers can be reached at:**

Dr. Stefanie Wegener, [privacypolicy@parship.co.uk](mailto:privacypolicy@parship.co.uk) (email) 

_Collection, processing and use of personal data_

The supply of your personal data is done voluntary in connectionwith the conclusion and existence of the contractual relationship with Parship. It is necessary that you indicate amongst others special categories of personal data (the gender you are looking for is a data concerning your sexual orientation ). If you do not want Parship to process your personal data and especially special categories of data, Parship will not be able to provide you with its service. Please refer to the following information for details of which data Parship collects in detail. 

**What data does Parship collect from its members to fulfill the contractual relationship?**

In order for Parship to perform the services fully described in the [General Terms and Conditions](https://uk.parship.com/termsandconditions/), it is necessary to collect, process and use personal data that the user (also referred to as a Parship-Member) indicates, inter alia, in connection with the registration process or the conclusion of a Basic-Membership or a Premium-Membership. 

**Registration process and conclusion of a Basic-Membership**

During the initial free registration (conclusion of the so-called "Basic-Membership"), the user (also called "Basic-Member") is required to provide certain minimum information without which the registration cannot be completed. These mandatory data are: 

  * Gender and searched gender (the gender you are looking for is a data regarding sexual orientation)
  * Email address 
  * Password 

Furthermore, further information, such as 

  * Post Code
  * Date of birth

can already be specified during the registration process. 

Access to Parship is made through the Email address and the password indicated by the user (so-called access data). 

Amongst others, following information are requested during the personality test that follows the registration 

  * Post Code
  * Date of birth
  * Marital status
  * Number of children
  * Education level
  * Occupation
  * Income

Furthermore, Parship needs further information from its users in order to perform its services, such as tastes, personal values, preferences, appearance, and other characteristics relevant for the personalised partner recommendations and that serve as a basis for the creation of the Parship-profile. As part of the profile, free text information and pictures of the Parship member could be included. From your answers to the Parship personality test, we automatically generate the so-called Parship personality profile. 

Parship identifies separately questions which answers should not be displayed to other users. All other data of the Parship profile are visible on the website and the app for other registered users. Also visible are data that are released by the user to other users, including age, postal code, interests, etc. 

Parship gives the possibility to indicate a mobile phone number for a so-called ID-Check or to receive SMS from Parship. The indication of a mobile phone number is not necessary to use Parship service. 

**At registration via Facebook ("Facebook Login")**

Parship offers you the opportunity to register via your Facebook account. If you use it, we will receive the data required for registration from Facebook. Due to that a data transfer is needed. 

We have no influence on the amount of data collected by Facebook via the Facebook login. If you do not want Facebook to collect information about you in connection with your use of our online service and use it for your own purposes, you should not use the Facebook login. 

For more information on the purpose and scope of the survey and the further processing and use of your data by Facebook, as well as your rights and options to protect your data, please refer to the Facebook Privacy Policy: <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>. 

**Completion of a premium membership**

If the user (hereinafter referred to as "premium member") decides to use a fee-based service of Parship (so-called "premium membership"), the following information will be collected within the order: 

  * Name and first name
  * Residential address
  * Payment and billing details (credit card details are stored by the payment provider and not by Parship)

**Communication with the members and the customer service**

Parship stores member communications and communication with customer service. The communication of the members in the logged-in state is encrypted. 

Please take into account the following when communicating with our customer service: If you communicate with our customer service using the contact form, this transmission is encrypted. The transmission of our reply to your request is encrypted, only if your email provider supports Transport Layer Security (TLS) transport encryption. Should you wish an e-mail communication with content encryption, please contact Parship by post or fax instead. You will find our contact details under Contact. 

**What information does Parship collect for promotional purposes?**

Upon conclusion of the free basic membership you enter your email address in the input mask. This email address will subsequently be used to send advertising emails for the free and paid products of PE Digital GmbH, without the need for your consent. You have the opportunity to object to the use of your email address for promotional purposes at any time. The Parship website also offers the option, by clicking a check box, of subscribing to a free newsletter. The data from the input mask are used when signing up to the newsletter. Again, you can always object to the use of your email address for the receipt of newsletters. You will also receive personalized or personalized guides during Parship membership to help you get the most out of your Parship products. Here you can find out which cookies Parship uses as part of advertising. 

**What information does Parship collect when using the Parship website?**

Within every access to the website Parship user data of the respective website visitors - unless otherwise stated below, even if they are not Parship members -is transmitted by the respective Internet browser and stored in log files. These data are: 

  * Information about the browser type and the internet service provider of the user as well as the used operating system (for example Windows 7, Apple OS, etc.)
  * IP address (Internet Protocol address) of the accessing computer, tablet or smartphone (In this case, the IP address is compared with a geo-database and the origin or country, state and city of the user are determined.)
  * User ID on the Parship platform (only by Parship members)
  * Name of the accessed page
  * Date and time of the call
  * The referrer URL (origin URL) from which the user came to the retrieved page
  * Transmitted amount of data
  * Status message as to whether the retrieval was successful
  * Session identification number
  * Used screen resolution

The so-called login records store the following usage data each time the Parship member logs in to the network: 

  * Date and time of login
  * User ID on the Parship platform
  * IP Address (Internet Protocol Address)
  * Number of session cookies
  * Session identification number
  * Meeting participants pseudonym

_Processing purposes_

Parship processes personal data of its users for the following purposes: 

  * To fulfill the services described in the [General Terms and Conditions](https://uk.parship.com/termsandconditions/). (Legal basis of the data collection is the fulfilment of the contractual relationship concluded with you as a Parship member.) Please note that we also collect sexual orientation data "gender and sex sought" in this context.
  * For abuse, prevention and defense. Parship will use the geodata and personal data collected in connection with your registration, the completion of the Parship Personality Test and the Parship Profile for an automated review of any evidence of abuse of the Parship website. The data are stored in a database under a pseudonym and compared with empirical values. If the automated processing reveals a suspicion of abuse, a Parship employee reviews the rating and the underlying clues, and then the free text information and profile pictures. Also, a customer service representative reviews reported breaches of contract by other members. Furthermore, Parship uses the optional indication of a mobile phone number in order to perform a secured identity check within the framework of the so-called ID-Check. (Legal basis is the legitimate interest of Parship and the Parship members that the Parship service is not abused for contractual and / or unlawful acts of third parties).
  * For automated price determination. (Legal basis is the fulfilment of the contractual relationship.)
  * For ensuring your remuneration obligations from the contractual relationship in the event of default. (The legal basis is apart from the fulfilment of the contractual relationship also the legitimate interest Parship in the payment of the contractually agreed remuneration.)
  * For the functionality of the website, to optimize and analyse the website and to ensure the security of the information technology systems of Parship. In this case, Parship uses technically necessary and unnecessary [cookies](https://www.parship.co.uk/static_cms/parship/static/Downloads/03_gb_Tracking_mechanism.pdf) or analysis cookies (legal basis is the legitimate interest of Parship and the Parship members that the Parship service can be used safely and easily and the quality of our website and content is constantly improving.)
  * For recording and evaluating user behavior for interest-based advertising (exclusively PE Digital products). In order to measure the performance of these advertising campaigns (so-called conversion tracking), we provide tracking data to third parties (such as Google and Microsoft). You will find further details under "Web analytics". (Legal basis is the legitimate interest of Parship and other advertisers to play interest-based advertising and to provide users with advertisements tailored to their personal interests.)
  * For the integration of social plugins and social share functions. (Legal basis is the legitimate interest of Parship, to comply with the request of the users who have activated a social plugin to share their information with the appropriate social network.
  * For self-advertising through unencrypted advertising emails, SMS or WhatsApp messages and advertisements in the form of banner advertising on other websites. (The legal basis is the legitimate interest of PE Digital GmbH in direct marketing for its own products.)
  * For sending various newsletters (via unencrypted e-mail, SMS or WhatsApp messages) in which you can find out more about the products of Parship. (The legal basis is the legitimate interest of Parship in direct marketing for its own products.)
  * For market research and range measurement. (The legal basis is Parship's legitimate interest in gaining insights into the market value of the Parship website in direct comparison with third-party websites.) The legitimate interest also arises from the economic exploitation of the findings resulting from the range measurement. The user categories form the basis for an interest-oriented alignment of advertising material and advertising measures. Here you can find further information.

_Legal basis for the processing of personal data_

  * Insofar as we obtain the consent of the data subject for processing of personal data, point (a) of Article 6(1) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) serves as the legal basis.
  * When processing personal data required to fulfill the contractual relationship of Parship (basic membership or premium membership), point (b) of Article 6(1) GDPR is the legal basis. This also applies to processing data required to carry out pre-contractual actions.
  * If processing is necessary to safeguard the legitimate interest of Parship or a third party, such as its members, and the interests, fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject do not prevail over the first mentioned interest, point (f) of Article 6(1) GDPR is the legal basis for processing.
  * If processing personal data required for self-promotion (Basic-Membership or Premium-Membership), point (f) of Article 6(1) GDPR is the legal basis for processing.

_Transfer of data to third parties; service provider_

Your personal data will only be given to third parties by Parship if this is necessary for the fulfilment of the contract or if your consent exists. If personal data is transmitted to third parties on the basis of a legitimate interest, we explain our legitimate interest in this privacy policy. 

In addition, personal data may be transferred to third parties, as far as Parship should be obliged to do so due to legal regulations or enforceable official or court orders. 

**Service provider**

Parship reserves the right to use service providers when collecting or processing personal data. Service providers receive from Parship only the personal data they need for their specific activity. 

Parship uses service provider for sending emails and newsletters to their members. In addition, service providers provide Parship server capacity. External payment services and collection-related service providers assist Parship with the settlement of payments. Depending on which payment method you choose in the order process, Parship will forward the data collected for processing payments (eg bank details or credit card information) to the payment institution or to the payment service provider appointed by Parship. In part, the payment service providers also collect these data in own responsibility. In this respect, the privacy policy of the respective payment service provider applies. 

Service providers are usually involved as so-called processor, who may process personal data of the users of this online service only according to instructions from Parship. 

**Transfer of data to non-EEA countries**

We also forward personal data to third parties or processors who are located outside EEA countries. In such cases we ensure prior to the transfer that the recipient is subject to an adequate level of data protection (e.g. on the basis of an Adequacy Decision of the EU Commission for the country in question, by self-certification of the recipient for the EU-US Privacy Shield or by having agreed upon so-called standard data protection clauses of the European Union with the recipient) or sufficient user consent is given. 

_Duration of storage; retention periods_

We store your data for as long as this is necessary for the provision of our online offer (basic and premium membership) and the associated services or we have a legitimate interest in the further storage. In all other cases, we will erase your personal information except for such information as we may need to maintain in order to fulfill contractual or statutory (e.g. tax or commercial) retention periods (e.g. invoices). 

For basic members: You can object to the storage of personal data contained in your profile at any time with future effect. You can also erase your profile data yourself. For basic members who are inactive for 24 months, Parship automatically erases personal profile data. 

For Premium members: The personal data of Parship Premium members are always stored for the duration of the contract. If you ask us to do so, we will erase your data, as long as there is no statutory storage obligation for these data. Data that is subject to a retention period, we lock until the expiry of the retention period. If you do not ask us to erase your data until the end of Premium Membership, your premium membership will be converted into a basic membership. The previously stated information on the duration of the storage of basic member data then applies. 

Please note that your data will initially be blocked only if deletion is prevented by retention periods. 

In the context of the assertion of data subject rights Parship stores those data, which are necessary for the fulfilment or the proof during the limitation period. 

_Rights of the data subject at a glance_

You have the right of access and, under certain conditions, to rectification, erasure, restriction of processing or to object to the processing of their personal data and to data portability. 

You can also object at any time with effect for the future to the processing of your personal data for advertising purposes ("object to advertising "). Please take into account that for organizational reasons there may be an overlap between your assertion of your right to object and the use of your data as part of an ongoing campaign. 

You have given us your information about your sexual orientation (gender and sex). You can assert your right to object this consent at any time with effect for the future. The lawfulness of the processing of your data until the assertion of your right to object remains unaffected. From the time of your withdrawal partner suggestions can no longer be made and Parship can no longer provide its service. 

Please use the information under Contact to assert your rights. Please make sure that we can clearly identify you. 

Alternatively, you can use the setting options in your profile to rectify your data provided during registration or for your object to advertising. You can also erase the data of your Parship base membership yourself. Erasure of premium membership data can only be initiated through Parship Customer Service. Please note that your data will initially only be blocked if the erasure is prevented by retention periods. 

**Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority**

You have the right to file a complaint with a data protection authority. You can contact the data protection authority, which is responsible for your place of residence or your state, or the data protection authority responsible for us. This is: 

Free and Hanseatic City of Hamburg, The Hamburg Commissioner for Data Protection and Freedom of Information, Prof. Dr. med. Johannes Caspar, E-Mail: [mailbox@datenschutz.hamburg.de](mailto:mailbox@datenschutz.hamburg.de)

_Cookies & web tracking_

This website uses cookies. Which cookies are used in detail can be found [here](https://www.parship.co.uk/static_cms/parship/static/Downloads/03_gb_Tracking_mechanism.pdf). In addition to the name of the individual cookies, we have also listed the intended purpose and other important information at this point. You can use Parship via the URL [tfv.parship.co.uk](https://tfv.parship.co.uk/) free from advertising cookies and analysis cookies. 

Cookies are small text files that are sent when you visit a website and stored in the browser of the user. If the corresponding Internet page is retrieved, the browser of the user sends back the content of the cookies and thus enables recognition of the user. Certain cookies are automatically erased after the end of the browser session (so-called session cookies), others are stored for a predetermined time or permanently in the user's browser and then erase themselves (so-called temporary or permanent cookies). 

In cookies, no personal data is stored, but only an online identifier. 

**What kind of cookies does Parship use?**

**Strictly necessary cookies**

Certain cookies are required to make our online offer safe and easy to use. This category includes 

  * Cookies that serve to identify or authenticate our users;
  * Cookies that temporarily store certain user entries;
  * Cookies that store certain user preferences.

**Analysis cookies**

We use analysis cookies to record the usage behavior (eg visited subpages) of our users and to evaluate them in statistical form. 

**Third Party Advertising Cookies / Third Party Pixel / Third Party Tracking**

We also allow other companies to collect our users' data through advertising cookies or pixels. This allows us and third parties to provide users of our online offering with interest-based advertising based on an analysis of their usage behavior (e.g., clicked banner ads, visited subpages) as a whole and not limited to our online offering. 

Which cookies / pixels are used in detail can be found [here](https://www.parship.co.uk/static_cms/parship/static/Downloads/03_gb_Tracking_mechanism.pdf). In addition to the name of the individual cookies / pixels, we have also listed the intended use and other important information there. You can use Parship via the URL [tfv.parship.co.uk](https://tfv.parship.co.uk/) free from advertising cookies and analysis cookies.

**How can you prevent the use of cookies or erase cookies?**

You can use Parship via the URL [tfv.parship.co.uk](https://tfv.parship.co.uk/) free from advertising cookies and analysis cookies. In this case, only the strictly necessary cookies that are necessary for the use of the website are used. 

Alternatively, you can deactivate the storage of cookies via your browser settings and erase already stored cookies at any time in your browser (see Technical Notes). Please note, however, that this online offer without cookies may not work or may only work to a limited extent. 

We also recommend the website of [www.YourOnlineChoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/), where you can get information and help in connection with web tracking mechanisms. 

_Web analytics_

We need statistical information about how we use our online offering to make it more user-friendly, to make range measurements, to conduct market research and to show relevant advertisements for you. For this purpose, we work with various authorised service providers and use web analytics tools. The tools either do not use users' IP addresses at all, or truncate them immediately after the survey. The usage profiles generated by the tools using analytic cookies or by evaluating the log files are not merged with personally identifiable information. The providers of the tools process data as processors according to our instructions and not for their own purposes. 

These providers are subject to their respective privacy policy. These providers are subject to their respective privacy policy. 

Which web analytics tracking mechanisms are used in detail can be found [here](https://www.parship.co.uk/static_cms/parship/static/Downloads/03_gb_Tracking_mechanism.pdf). In addition to the description of the individual tracking mechanisms, we have also listed the intended use and other important information at this point. You can use Parship via the URL [tfv.parship.co.uk](https://tfv.parship.co.uk/) free from web analytics tracking mechanisms. 

You can use Parship via the URL [tfv.parship.co.uk](https://tfv.parship.co.uk/) free from advertising cookies and analysis cookies. In this case, only the strictly necessary cookies that are necessary for the use of the website are used. 

We also recommend the website of [www.YourOnlineChoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/), where you can get information and help in connection with web tracking mechanisms. 

**Google Analytics**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Ireland Ltd, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies that are stored on your computer, tablet or smartphone and that allow an analysis of your use of the website. These are cookies from Google itself (Google Analytics cookies). Parship uses Google Analytics with the additional feature offered by Google for the anonymization of IP addresses: Google's IP address is usually already shortened within the EU and only in exceptional cases only in the US and in any case only in abbreviated form. On behalf of Parship, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity, and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage, such as Google Analytics demographics and interest reports, to provide to Parship. How Google processes data is described [here](https://privacy.google.com/businesses/processorterms/). 

Unused by Parship will be the Google Analytics Advertising Features. 

You can use Parship via the URL [tfv.parship.co.uk](https://tfv.parship.co.uk/) free from advertising cookies and analysis cookies. In this case, only the strictly necessary cookies that are necessary for the use of the website are used. 

**Using Google Ads Conversion Tracking**

Parship uses the Google Ads online advertising program and Google Ads conversion tracking. Google Conversion Tracking is an analytics service provided by Google Ireland Ltd, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland ("Google"). When you click on an ad served by Google, a conversion tracking cookie will be placed on your computer, tablet or smartphone. These cookies lose their validity after 90 days. If you visit certain web pages on our website and the cookie has not expired, Google and we may recognize that you clicked on the ad and were redirected to this page. Each Google Ads customer receives a different cookie. 

The information gathered using the conversion cookie is used to generate conversion statistics for Ads advertisers who have opted for conversion tracking. It tells customers the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a conversion tracking tag page. However, they do not receive information that personally identifies users. 

You can use Parship via the URL [tfv.parship.co.uk](https://tfv.parship.de/) free from advertising cookies and analysis cookies. In this case, only the strictly necessary cookies that are necessary for the use of the website are used. 

**Use of Google Ads remarketing function**

Parship uses the online advertising program “Google Ads” and within this framework, conversion tracking (evaluation of user actions). The Google conversion tracking is an analysis service provided by Google Ireland Ltd, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland (“Google”). This feature allows Parship to target visitors to the website with advertising by delivering personalized, interest-based ads to Parship visitors when they visit other websites on the Google Display Network or use Google's or a partner's search function. Google uses cookies to analyze website usage, which forms the basis for creating interest-based advertising. To do this, Google saves a small file with a sequence of numbers in the browser of Parship users. Through this sequence of numbers visit of Parship and data regarding the use of Parship will be recorded. If users subsequently visit other websites on the Google Display Network or the search function of Google or a partner, Parship will display advertisements to visitors that are highly likely to include previously accessed product and information areas. 

You can use Parship free from web analysis cookies through the URL [tfv.parship.co.uk](https://tfv.parship.de/) In this case, only the strictly necessary cookies, which are necessary for the use of the website, remain in place. 

You can permanently deactivate the use of cookies by Google by following the link below and downloading and installing the plug-in provided there: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. Alternatively, you can disable the use of cookies by third parties by visiting the deactivation page of the Network Advertising Initiative at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> and implementing the additional opt-out information mentioned there. For more information about Google Remarketing and Google's privacy policy, please visit <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl=en>

**Social plugins**

The integration of social plugins regularly leads to the providers of the plugins storing cookies. The various providers of plugins are summarized below under the term "plugin provider". 

In order to increase the protection of your data when visiting our online service, the plugins are integrated into the site via the so-called "Shariff solution". This ensures that when you call up a page of this online offer, no connection is established with the servers of the respective plug-in provider. 

Only when the plugins are activated by you, your Internet browser establishes a direct connection to the servers of the respective plugin provider. This gives the plugin provider the information that your Internet browser has accessed the corresponding page of our online service, even if you do not have a user account with the provider or are currently not logged in. Log files (including the IP address) are transmitted from your Internet browser directly to a server of the respective plugin provider and possibly stored there. This server may be located outside the EU or the EEA (for example, in the U.S.A.). 

The plugins represent independent extensions of the plugin providers. Therefore, we have no influence on the extent of the plugin providers collected and stored by the plugins data. 

If you do not want the plug-in providers to receive the data collected via this Internet portal and to save or re-use them, you should not use the respective plug-ins. 

Basically, you can completely prevent the plugins from being loaded with add-ons for your browser, so-called script blockers. 

Further information on the purpose and scope of the survey as well as the further processing and use of your data by plug-in providers as well as your rights and setting options for the protection of your data can be found in the privacy policy of the respective provider. 

Parship uses social plugins ("plugins") from the following providers: 

**Social plugins from Facebook**

Plugins of the social network Facebook; Facebook will be available at [www.facebook.com](https://www.facebook.com/) from Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA, and at [en-gb.facebook.com](https://en-gb.facebook.com/) from Facebook Ireland Limited, Hanover Reach, 5-7 Hanover Quay, Dublin 2 , Ireland, ("Facebook"). An overview of the plugins of Facebook and their appearance can be found here <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/>; You can find information about data protection on Facebook here: <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>

**Social plugins from Twitter**

Plugins from Twitter; Twitter is operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA ("Twitter"). An overview of Twitter's plug-ins and information on data protection on Twitter here: <https://twitter.com/privacy>

**Social Plugins from Google+**

Plugins of the social network Google+; Google+ is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). For an overview of Google+ plugins and their looks, see: <https://developers.google.com/+/plugins>; For privacy information on Google+, please visit: <http://www.google.com/intl/de/+/policy/+1button.html>

**Appendix: Technical Notes Cookies**

(Please use Parship completely ad-free via the URL [tfv.parship.co.uk](https://tfv.parship.co.uk/)) 

**Internet Explorer:**

Instructions at <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies#ie=ie-11-win-7>

**Mozilla Firefox:**

Instructions at <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored>

**Google Chrome:**

Instructions at <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647>

**Safari:**

Instructions at <https://support.apple.com/en-gb/guide/safari/manage-cookies-and-website-data-sfri11471/mac>
